So now, here is how the Hidden Markov Model generates a sentence.
我们来看看隐马尔可夫模型是如何生成句子的
We start by placing ourselves at the start.
我们从起始部分开始
And with some probability,
根据某个概率
we walk around the hidden states.
在隐藏状态之间移动
Let's say we walk into the N of noun.
假设转到名词 N 处
Once we're at the N, then we have some options to generate observations.
来到 N 后 可以选择生成一些观察结果
So let's say with some probability,
假设根据某个概率
we generate the word, Jane.
生成了单词 Jane
So we record this word.
记下这个单词
Then we walk around the hidden states some more.
然后继续在隐藏状态之间移动
Let's say we land on the M for modal and this generates the word Will.
假设来到情态动词 M 处 生成单词 will
So, we record this and then we walk to the V of verb and generate the word spot.
记下这个单词 然后转到动词 V 处 生成单词 spot
Record that then walk to the N of noun and generate the word Will.
记下该单词 继续转到名词 N 处 生成单词 Will
And finally, we walk to the end state and generate the end of the sentence or a period.
最后来到结束状态 生成句子的结束内容 即句号
And when we reach this, we're done.
到达此状态后就结束了
Now, it is clear that most sentences can be generated this way.
很明显大部分句子都可以这么生成
So now, what we'll do is we'll record the probability of the sentence being generated.
现在我们将记录生成该句子的概率
So, we start again at the starting state.
再次从起始状态开始
And as we remember,
注意
we walked to the N. The transition probability from
我们转到 N
the start state to N is three-quarters.
从起始状态到 N 的概率是 3/4
So we'll record this three-quarters.
记下 3/4
Now, at N we generate the word Jane.
现在 在 N 处生成单词 Jane
This happens with emission probability two-ninths,
发生概率是发射概率 2/9
so we record that.
记下该数字
Now, we move to M and the transition probability is
转到 M 转移概率是 1/3
one-third and generate Will with emission probability of three-quarters.
生成 will 发射概率是 3/4
Then, we move to V with
然后转到 V
transition probability three-quarters and generate
转移概率为 3/4
spot with the emission probability one-quarter.
生成 spot 发射概率是 1/4
Then, we move back to N with transition probability
回到 N 转移概率是 1
one and we generate Will with emission probability one over nine.
生成 Will 发射概率是 1/9
Finally, we move to the end state with transition probability four over nine.
最后 转到结束状态 转移概率是 4/9
So, since the transition moves are all independent of each other and
因为转移动作相互独立
the emission moves are conditional on the hidden state that were located at,
发射动作取决于所在位置的隐藏状态
the probability that this Hidden Markov Model
因此这个隐马尔可夫模型生成一个句子的概率
generates a sentence is the product of these probabilities.
是这些概率的积
We multiply them and get the total probability of the sentence
我们将这些概率相乘
being emitted is 0.0003858.
得出生成这个句子的概率为 0.0003858
It looks small, but actually it's large considering
看起来很小 但考虑到我们可以生成大量长度不等的句子
the huge amount of sentences we can generate of many lengths.
实际上这个概率很大了
So let's repeat this path for,
我们重复下这个路径
Jane will spot Will.
Jane will spot Will.
We have the parts of speech noun, modal, verb, noun
词性为名词 情态动词 动词 名词
and the probabilities, and their product is 0.0003858.
具有这些概率 积为 0.0003858
Let's see if another path can generate this sentence.
我们来看看另一个路径是否能生成该句子
What about the path noun noun noun noun?
名词-名词-名词-名词呢？
We hope this is smaller since it's a bit of a nonsensical pattern of parts of speech.
希望这个概率很小 因为似乎是不合理的词性组合
And indeed, it is very small.
实际上概率很小
It is the product of these numbers which is 0.0000002788.
它是这些数字的积 结果为 0.0000002788
So, among these two,
在这两个路径中
we pick the one on top because it generates the sentence with a higher probability.
我们选择上面的路径 因为它生成该句子的概率更高
And in general, what we'll do is from all the possible combinations of parts of speech,
通常我们的做法是 从所有可能的词性组合中
we'll pick the one that generates the sentence,
选择生成句子
Jane will spot Will,
Jane will spot Will.
with the highest probability.
概率最高的组合
This is called maximum likelihood.
称之为最大似然率
It's the core of many algorithms and artificial intelligence. So that's simple.
它是很多算法和人工智能的核心
All we have to do is go over all the possible chains
方法很简单 我们只需查看能够生成相关句子的
of parts of speech that could generate the sentence.
所有可能的词性组合
So, let's have a small quiz.
我们来做一道练习
How many of these chains are there?
这里有多少个词性组合？